Kalindu De Costa

kalinduk.decosta@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Experienced software developer with a diverse set of technical and interpersonal skills with excellent software design and development abilities acquired through professional work experiences such as the Software Developer position at IBM and educational and personal projects like UTSC Document Search and Art of Guessing. Experience in team management techniques like Agile, Scrum acquired through all work experiences and personal projects.

Links

- kdecosta.com
- in linkedin.com/in/kdecosta
- github.com/kalindudc

Languages

Java, Python, C, C#, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Haskell, Scheme, SH/Bash

Tools / Operating Systems

Unity, Microsoft Office, Photoshop, Balsamiq, JustInMind, Maven, Windows, Linux

Design Principles

Agile/Scrum, OOP, UML, CRC Cards, HCl, Design Patterns and Concepts

Frameworks / Databases

NodeJS, Tomcat, React, Express, SocketIO, AWS, Google API, MongoDB, Oracle

Experience

IBM- InfoSphere Data Replication Software Developer

SEPT 2016 - JAN 2018

- Extensively worked with RTC/GIT version control and the IBM mainframe systems like IBM Z and the iSeries.
- Worked considerably towards QA which involves with integration testing, functional testing and unit testing successfully to resolve and reduce bugs and defects.
- Attended to customer complaints (L3), found and resolved product defects and wrote private documentation and public documentation which eased the day-today development for the team as well as the customers.
- Worked on various databases such as DB2 LUW, DB2 mainframe, Oracle and Netezza as well as other systems such as Apache Hadoop and Confluent Kafka and gained valuable insight on project workflows.
- Trained new developers on CDC systems and software / design techniques.

University of Toronto – Teaching Assistant

SEPT 2015 - PRESENT

- Planned and taught a weekly 1-hour lesson for various Computer Science courses to a group of 30 students which enhanced knowledge and understanding of core Computer Science topics and led to a successful semester for all my students.
- Used presentations techniques like live coding, power point presentations and written work on the black board to extend and enrich the lecture material.

FCS Canada – Event Coordinator / Web Master

JUN 2015 - AUG 2015

- Developed and implemented media and marketing campaigns for events, programs and major organizational initiatives accomplished through the successful annual summer community event.
- Managed and maintained all online communication services, including FCS's website and social media which involved development in HTML/CSS and JavaScript demonstrated through various sponsorships and publicity.
- Assisted in all aspects of events including logistics, promotional materials, staffing, and fundraising efforts.

Education

University of Toronto – Honours Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.)

SEPT 2014 - APR 2019

Specializing in Software Engineering (Co-op)

Projects

UTSC Document Search - File Indexer and File Search

TOMCAT, MongoDB, AWS-S3

Complete search engine with a fully functional file indexer along with user accounts and notifications built using Java, Tomcat and Lucene for the backend and HTML/CSS and JavaScript for the frontend.

The Art of Guessing - Real time web based multiplayer browser game

NodeJS, SocketIO, MongoDB, Restful

A WebSocket based multiplayer drawing game completed using NodeJS and SocketIO. This application contains a fully functional user account system along with user statistics, public multiplayer matchmaking and private lobbies.

Eventalicious - *Interactive prototype for a web-based application*

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Google API, HCI

Interactive prototype for a web application that will enable users to connect with others in real time by projecting various nearby events and item promotions surrounding the user. This application was built using HCI principles with a User Centered design.